Diogo Ferreira

Software Engineer



Diogo Ferreira From Portugal, living in Belgium Fluent in Portuguese and English

Programming Languages

Java • Kotlin • Python

Frameworks & Libraries

Spring • Quarkus • Apache Camel • Django • Akka • Flink • FastAPI

Cloud & DevOps

Kubernetes • Docker • AWS • Azure • Google Cloud • Helm • GitHub Actions

Tools & Databases

Kafka • RabbitMQ • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Elasticsearch

- diogodsferreira
 @gmail.com
- diogodsferreira .github.io
- in diogo-ferreira
- odiogodaniel soaresferreira

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience building scalable, distributed systems in the cloud. I specialize in Java, Kotlin and Python, and have a strong focus on clean architecture, observability and reliability at scale. I regularly share engineering insights and lessons learned on my blog.

EXPERIENCE

12/2023-

Timefold

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · Remote (Belgium)

Designed and implemented a platform-as-a-service for scheduling opti-

mization workloads (eg. employee shifts, vehicle routing). Used Java and Quarkus, deploying to Kubernetes across multiple cloud providers (AWS, Azure, GCP), enabling customers to run complex planning

jobs efficiently and at scale.

11/2021-11/2023

Blip

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · Remote (Portugal)

Built and maintained event-driven microservices for brands like Betfair, PaddyPower and FanDuel as part of Flutter Entertainment Group, the world's leading online sports betting and gaming operator.

Worked primarily with Java, Kotlin and Scala, using Akka, Kafka, Spring and Flink to ensure scalable and observable systems in a high-traffic environment.

09/2019-

11/2021

TalkdeskSoftware Engineer · Remote (Portugal)

Developed data-driven backend services at a unicorn startup leading the global cloud contact center market.

Used Java, Quarkus and Apache Camel to build robust pipelines on AWS, processing 4+ million events daily with a focus on monitoring, reliability and scalability.

10/2017-08/2019

Instituto de Telecomunicações

STUDENT RESEARCHER · Aveiro, Portugal

Design and implementation of a distributed real-time architecture to forecast anomalies using machine learning techniques and act on the network to improve the quality of service.

Develop a platform with support for management, monitoring, alerts and actuation over the data of a city, in real-time (smart city) using Python and Django.

07/2016-

Aptoide

SOFTWARE INTERN · Lisbon, Portugal

Design and build a software with the purpose of finding apps in the Aptoide Store with explicit content using Python and Machine Learning techniques, with accuracy greater than 95%.



BLIP.

ŧt

EDUCATION

2014-2019

Integrated MSc in Computer and Telematics Engineering

 ${\tt STUDENT} \cdot {\sf Aveiro University}$

Finished with a grade of 18.21, being the best student of the course finishing in 2018/2019, having a dissertation grade of 20/20 and having received a merit award.

